uow.edu.au 2018-12-28

# Privacy Statement - About the University @ UOW

## What is privacy?

According to the [Information and Privacy Commission](http://www.ipc.nsw.gov.au/), Privacy can mean the right to a sense of personal freedom, the right to be left alone and most importantly, the right to have information about oneself handled in a fair and proper manner.

## Privacy legislation

UOW must handle your personal and health information in accordance with NSW's  _Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act 1998_ and _Health Records and Information Privacy Act 2002_.  These Acts set out the privacy principles that UOW must abide by when it collects, stores, uses and discloses personal and health information.

## UOW's privacy obligations

UOW is committed to protecting and maintaining the privacy of your personal and health information. UOW's Privacy Policy and Privacy Management Plan demonstrate our commitment to protecting your privacy and provide details of:

  * the ways in which UOW complies with its privacy obligations;
  * policies and practices that address UOW's privacy responsibilities; and
  * procedures relating to handling grievances or complaints regarding UOW's privacy practices.

UOW's Privacy Information Sheet provides a summary of the information protection principles that UOW must comply with when handling your personal and health information.

## Collection

UOW collects your personal and/or health information for lawful purposes that are directly related to UOW's functions or activities.  When UOW collects your personal and/or health information, you will be informed as to why it is being collected, what will be done with it, whether it's required by law and your rights of access to and correction of that information.

The Student Privacy and Disclosure Statement lists the intended use/disclosure of personal and/or health information collected from students. This Statement also provides details of how students can request access or seek amendments to their personal and/or health information.

The Privacy Collection Statement for Recruitment and Employee Records provides details of the types of information collected from employees and/or prospective employees, how that information is held and used by UOW,  circumstances where it may be disclosed and details of how the employee can access his/her record. 

The Privacy Statement for UOW's alumni, donors and members of the community provides details of the way that it connects with and handles the information of its alumni, donors and community when engaging with UOW.

## Security

UOW takes all reasonable steps to protect your personal and/or health information against loss, misuse, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. 

UOW's Data Breach Response Plan provides a consistent set of procedures that UOW will follow in the event of a data breach. This plan will ensure that appropriate steps are taken to respond promptly and appropriately, in accordance with the NSW Information and Privacy Commission best practice.

## Disclosure

UOW will NOT disclose your personal or health information unless:

  * you have provided clear and written consent to do so;
  * a court or similar body has ordered the information’s release;
  * a law enforcement agency is requiring information and certain tests are met; or
  * the disclosure is necessary to prevent a serious and imminent threat to your life or health or that of another person.  

## Uow website privacy statement

### Information collected online by UOW

When you visit UOW’s website, our servers may collect the following information: your IP address, browser type, operating system, pages viewed while browsing UOW’s website, dates and times of the visit. We use this information for statistical purposes and to help us improve our services. We may also use this information for marketing purposes.

Where your personal information is collected while visiting our site, we will provide you with details about the purpose for collecting it including how it will be used, whether it’s required by or under law and if it’s to be disclosed to any other party. We will only use your personal information for the purpose for which you provided it or a directly related purpose.

### Use of cookies

UOW uses cookies to identify user traffic patterns on its website. Information collected from cookies is used for statistical analysis purposes so that UOW can provide you with a website that best meets your needs. It may also be used as a basis for targeting online advertising. A cookie in no way provides access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with UOW.

Some UOW sites may use cookies for authentication purposes or to personalise your web experience. For example, a cookie within the UOW Course Finder will remember the courses you previously viewed.

UOW also uses Google cookies for remarketing to advertise online. When you visit our website, our web server will drop a cookie on your browser. If you leave our website and visit another website which is part of the Google network, you may be served our advertisement.

You may disable cookies by adjusting your web browser, but if you do some of our sites might not be accessible to you.

### Security

UOW has a number of security measures in place to protect against IT security risks. These include firewalls, network intrusion detection and virus scanning. Refer to UOW’s IT Security Policy for further information.

Some UOW sites can only be accessed with a login name and password to ensure that only authorised users are able to access personal information. You should ensure that your password is kept securely and not accessible by others.

### Links to other websites

External sites that are linked to or from the UOW site are generally not under our control or responsibility. If you decide to access linked third-party websites, you are encouraged to review their privacy policy, terms of use and content.

### Privacy complaints

Any student, staff member or member of the public who is concerned about how their personal or health information is being handled by UOW should contact a privacy officer in UOW's Legal Services Unit.  The privacy officer will discuss your concerns or complaints and endeavour to reach a suitable resolution, referring to any existing UOW policies or complaint handling guidelines.

Where an individual wishes to make a formal request for a review of UOW's conduct in the handling of his/her personal or health information, the Privacy Complaint Internal Review Application Form is to be completed and lodged with the Legal Services Unit.

## Who to contact about privacy

Your first contact for any privacy-related matters should be Carmel Perre, who is UOW's Manager, Information Compliance.  Carmel's contact details are as follows:

**Carmel Perre  
**Manager, Information Compliance  
Legal Services  
Building 36, Level 4  
University of Wollongong NSW 2522

Phone: (02) 4221 4368  
Fax: (02) 4221 4254  
Email: [privacy-enquiry@uow.edu.au](mailto:privacy-enquiry@uow.edu.au) or [carmelp@uow.edu.au](mailto:carmel_perre@uow.edu.au)

If Carmel is not available, you should contact one of the lawyers in the Legal Services Unit. Phone (02) 4221 5202 or email [legal-enquiry@uow.edu.au](mailto:legal-enquiry@uow.edu.au)

## Tips and resources

The NSW Information and Privacy Commission (IPC) has developed a comprehensive range of resources to help members of the public understand their privacy rights. These resources include a fact sheet['A guide to protecting your privacy in NSW'](http://www.ipc.nsw.gov.au/sites/default/files/file_manager/FS-Guide-to-protecting-your-privacy-June14.pdf) and tips when communicating and sharing information on the internet, smartphones and social network sites.  

Visit the IPC's website for [further resources](http://www.ipc.nsw.gov.au/resources-public-0).

Last reviewed: 15 October, 2018
